

Email: <a href="mailto:consultant@londonresearchinternational.com">consultant@londonresearchinternational.com</a> www.LondonResearchInternational.com

# Mr. Ekpu

**NATIONALITY**: Nigerian

## **SUMMARY**

Mr.Ekpu is an economist qualified PhD from University of Glasgow. As well as having experiences in teaching at university, he has experiences in financial sector – including banking and financial services. Based on those work experience in banks, he is currently working as a managing consultant/ director of research & public policy at Mindset Resource Consulting Ltd in Glasgow, United Kingdom.

#### **EDUCATION**

- University of Glasgow (UK/ September 2010- September 2014), PhD Economics (Expected)
- University of Glasgow (UK/ September 2008- September 2009), MSc Economics,
  Banking and Finance
  - Graduated with Distinction
- Delta State University (Nigeria/ February 2001 December 2004), BSc Economics
  - Graduated with Upper Second Class Division
- C.M.S Grammar School (Bargia, Lagos, Nigeria/ January 1995- July 1999), West African Senior School Certificate

## **EMPLOYMENT RECORD**

- Mindset Resource Consulting Ltd (Glasgow, UK/ February 2010 present)
  - > Job Title: Managing Consultant/Director of Research & Policy Development
- Hudson Global Resources Limited (Glasgow, UK/ Oct 2012- Jan 2013)
  - Client: National Australia Bank Group, Europe (NAGE)
  - > Job Title: Administrator
- Zenith Bank Plc (Lagos, Nigeria/November 2006 September 2006)
  - Job Title: Senior Executive Assistant (SEA)
  - Adam Smith Business School, University of Glasgow (Glasgow, UK/ September 2011- March 2013)



Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com www.LondonResearchInternational.com

Job Title: Teaching Fellow in Economics

> Adam Smith Business School, University of Glasgow (Glasgow, UK/

September 2011- March 2013)

Job Title: Teaching Fellow in Economics

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Research & Training Consultancy**

- Central Bank of Nigeria (CBN); July-August 2013, Glasgow (UK) and New York (USA)
  - Seminar topics are following: Licensing of Financial Holding Companies,
    Qualitative Consolidated Supervision, Quantitative Consolidated
    Supervision, Rating System for Evaluating FHCs, Supervisory Challenges in the Application of Consolidated Supervision
- ➤ CBN with Centre for Banking and Finance, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill School of Law (USA); May 2013
  - Developing the Legal and Policy Framework for the Regulation and Supervision of Bank Holding Companies in Nigeria.
- CBN with Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City (USA); June 2012
  - The Regulation and Supervision of Bank Holding Companies in the USA:
    Implications for the Transition of Nigerian Banks to Holding Company
    Status
- > CBN (Ijebu Ode & Kaduna, Nigeria); Oct 2011
  - Promoting Financial Stability through Effective Regulation, Risk-Based Supervision and Governance in the Nigerian Financial Services Sector.

## **Other Research Consultancy Projects and Experiences**

- ➤ The Economics of Scottish Independence: A Cost-Benefit Analysis on the Restructuring of Public Service Companies in Key Sectors of the Current Scottish Economy (2013)
- > The Leasing Industry in Saudi Arabia (2012)
- ➤ Trading strategies for options and futures, technical & market analysis, and price correlations between commodities quoted in the financial markets (2012) with Energy Futures Capital Ltd. (UK)



Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com

www.LondonResearchInternational.com

- Data Management
- Credit Scoring Solutions
- Debt Management & Recovery
- > Enterprise Risk Solutions

## **Banking & Financial Services Experience**

➤ Hudson Global Resources Limited (Glasgow, UK/ Oct 2012- Jan 2013)

Job Title: Administrator

- Complaints handling and resolution
- Data gathering and research
- Investigating and responding to complaints
- Managing customer communications
- Liaison with third parties, i.e. Claims Management Companies and the Financial Ombudsman Service (FOS)
- Offering redress to customers where appropriate, including fair compensation for financial and nonfinancial losses to customers
- Case filing, electronic documentation, reporting and analysis
- Reworking of cases to ensure compliance with company policies and appropriate regulations
- Database management
- Zenith Bank Plc (Lagos, Nigeria/ November 2006- September 2008)

Job Title: Senior Executive Assistant (SEA)

- Processing Cash, Cheque, Card and Other Electronic Payment Transactions
- Customer Account Reconciliations
- Product Sales and Customer Relationship Management
- Responsible for Managing three (3) of the bank's Cash Offices in CHI Ltd,
  NAHCO and Arik Air Ltd,
- Reporting to the main branch's Head of Operations and ultimately to the Branch Head/AGM

#### **Academic Experience**

Adam Smith Business School, University of Glasgow (Glasgow, UK/

September 2011- March 2013)

Job Title: Teaching Fellow in Economics



Email: <a href="mailto:consultant@londonresearchinternational.com">consultant@londonresearchinternational.com</a> www.LondonResearchInternational.com

#### PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

- Affiliate Member, Global Association of Risk Professionals (GARP), Since 2013
- Member, Institute of Leadership and Management (ILM), UK, Since 2012
- Student Member, Scottish Institute for Research in Economics (SIRE), Since 2010
- Student Member, Royal Economic Society (RES), Since 2008
- Graduate Member, Nigerian Institute of Management (Chartered), Since 2006

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- 'Credit Risk Management and Supervision in the Context of Basel II and III', (Work-In-Progress)
- 'Consolidated Supervision of Banks and Financial Holding Companies', A Handbook for Central Bankers, (In Press) – co-author
- 'Promoting Financial Stability After the Crisis', A Handbook for Central Bankers, (Work-In-Progress)
- 'An Investigative Enquiry into the IT. Systems Failure in Royal Bank of Scotland Group',
  Essays on Operational Risk Management in Banking, December, 2012
- 'Bank Size, Ownership and the Profitability of Commercial Lending by UK Banks',
  Presented at the PhD Economics Seminar Series, University of Glasgow, May 2, 2012
- 'Rationale for Financial System Regulation: A Global Perspective', Bullion, Publication of the Central Bank of Nigeria Vol. 35, No. 4, Oct-Dec, 2011
- 'Risk Typology and Risk Mitigation under Basel II & III, Paper presented at a CBN Training Course, Oct 2011
- 'Strengthening Liquidity Risk Management in Nigerian Banks', Paper presented at a CBN Training Course, Oct 2011
- 'Strengthening the Macro-prudential Perspective of Financial Regulation and Supervision', Paper presented at a CBN Training Course, Oct 2011
- 'Credit Scoring in Small Business Lending: Do Large Banks Have an Advantage? (Paper presented at Credit Scoring and Credit Control Conference XII, University of Edinburgh Business School), August 24-26, 2011



Email: <a href="mailto:consultant@londonresearchinternational.com">consultant@londonresearchinternational.com</a> www.LondonResearchInternational.com

- 'Small Business Lending by Large and Small Banks: A Literature Survey', Paper presented at the SGPE PhD Conference at Crieff Hydro Hotel, Crieff, Scotland, Jan 14, 2011
- 'Financial Development, Financial Structure and Economic Growth in Nigeria', MSc
  Dissertation, Center for Development Studies, University of Glasgow, September, 2009
- 'Still on the Global Financial Crisis: The Micro- and Macro-economic Origins of the Financial Crisis' (News Paper Article), *Punch on the Web*, Tuesday June 9, 2009.
- 'External Debt and Economic Growth: A Review of Nigeria's Experience: 1983-2002',
  BSc Dissertation, Department of Economics, Delta State University, 2004

L	Α	N	G	U.	Α	G	ES

English